Commanders family, welcome in to a
special next man up. It's free agency
Fridays here in Big Bear AI Command
Center Studio and we got a big dog in
the building fresh off of getting some
paper and welcoming back Tim settled to
the building. What's up, brother?
>> What's happening with you, man? It's
amazing to be back. I'm I'm happy to be
back in my environment.
>> First things first, congratulations,
man. That's a major thing, brother. Put
pen to paper just now
>> and you come back home, man. Is is it
surreal being back in this building?
>> It's surreal, you know, especially uh
when you leave out when like it's when
you leave a team after like your last
year is up. It's like you like, "Dang,
will I ever come back here again?"
>> And it's like, "Dang, I'm back up in
here, man." And it's it's a surreal
moment. It's like I'll never forget it's
like we talking about it and you know
like I I I take pride in like coaching
and and organizations and and like how
things just ran and you know uh a lot of
things go off word of mouth but you know
like being able to play for DQ is big
man like just just hearing hearing just
the the the feedback from his former
players and you got that's that's what
that's what it's about when you got guys
that can play for the coach.
It's it it just hits different, you
know, uh because it's like when you got
coaches that that want to see you do
better than you want to see do yourself
do, it's like dang. So it's like that
I'm just getting in the environment of
of that.
>> Yeah, for sure man. And it's home for
you from Manasses, went to school out
here again, was drafted here. Does it
feel a little different being in the
building this time around?
>> It do. It do. like uh I feel like you
know when you first come out of the
draft and you know to the NFL it's like
you know like dang you it's more of like
dang this is my favorite this is my
favorite team it's my own team it's like
now it's like man I'm here to win
>> you know I'm here to win you know uh
>> shoot I my last four years you know I
luckily I've been able to make the
playoffs and you know just and I
wouldn't have came here if I didn't see
that picture you know I wouldn't I
didn't see that that the the the vision
here Mhm.
>> You know, you got a quarterback that
that's promising, you know, you got a
you got a a offense that that's
promising and you put together these
pieces on defense that can make this
defense promising. And it's like, you
know, you got a promising team, you
know, uh obviously, you know, uh being
in the playoffs, you know, you you know
what it takes. Yeah. You know, you know
what it looks like and you know, uh I
just want I just want to be able to add
me to what's already here and you know,
be able to help everything around it.
>> Yeah. Because it's like it's one thing
coming home, but at the end of the day,
this is your livelihood. This is your
family's livelihood, right? So, you're
making a business decision to come back
and like you said, it's because of those
things you see saw and you said DQ, he
was a big part of that. Can you
elaborate a little more on what are
those things you are hearing about Dan
Quinn? Maybe some of your interactions
you've had with him that makes you say,
"Yo, this is the place for me."
>> It with me, I'm I'm more of a a self
experience. I remember watching the
game. I don't remember what game it
probably last year, but
>> DQ got in the way of a play and he got
knocked on the ground and it's just like
>> he got back up, man. It's just like
you see that happen to anybody else,
man, they might need some medical
attention or anything. But you got
somebody that's willing to bounce back
up after a collision like in a in a
hostile environment, which I'm talking
about a game, it's like that's like that
right there. It's like whoa. It's like
okay. It's like that's what we playing
for. That's who you playing for. And it
just kind of give you a different like I
don't know that's that that give you
like you know I'm a I think of myself as
a dog and dog mentality when you see dog
mentality everybody don't really have
that but when you see like a like you
know kind of like a leader like the that
you know like with wolves you know they
always got that one leader you know when
you see a leader bounce back up off off
some stuff like that it's like all right
okay I can go to war with him I can go
to war with him because he might he
might get dirty with us you know what
I'm saying? So it's like and you know
I'm a trench I'm I'm in the trenches. So
I'm I'm physical nasty violent. That's
how I think. You know when you and you
see something like that it's just like
you know when the shark in the water you
know they smell blood.
>> Shoot. You better hide. You better get
about that water.
>> Where does Tim Settle get that dog from?
I see your pops in the building man.
Y'all all smiles walking in. Where do
you get that dog and all that motivation
from on that field?
>> I get it from my dad. You know uh
>> shoot. He tell me what it is. you know,
it's not around it's not a lot of
beating around the bush. You know, we
get a lot of like, you know, real real
emotional when it comes to football. We
get we talk real personal and we take
everything personal. You know, it's
like, you know, if you going to be a top
dog in the league, you know, you got to
you got to act like one. And, you know,
I feel like my dad has has did an
outstanding job as far as leading me and
guiding me in the right direction and
telling me when I'm right and when I'm
wrong. And you know, uh, you know, I
feel like you only can get as far as you
want off the people you listen to and
the people you follow.
>> So, you know, uh, with the proper
guidance, man, you can conquer anything
in the world.
>> And Tim, you played four seasons here in
Washington, took some time away, now
you're back. What changed about you from
the last time you was in this building?
>> It's my mindset. You know, uh, I
remember when I was here, I used to look
at the sideline all the time. My dad can
tell you this right now. I used to look
at the sideline after every two plays
looking for somebody to run on the field
with me, run on the field for me. You
know, getting dropped the fifth round,
you know, you you know, it's like you
you know what I'm saying? You just you
just looking for what's next instead of
knowing what's going on,
>> right? And you know, like my difference
now is I understand this league. You
know, I've been playing against this
league. You know, uh, and I've been
dominating in this league. You know, I
feel like I don't want to let that
overgo cuz anybody that that is somebody
or has something or that's a offensive
lineman with a name, I'm trying to see
about you. Like, have you met me?
>> You know my name. M
>> uh and I just I try to take that from
them because at the end of the day when
you get two alphas and you go against
going against each other, one got to
give eventually
>> and shoot you going to have to you going
to have to hurt me cuz I'm trying to
hurt you, man. I love that because you
have been so dominant, but then your
last season ends with an injury and
somebody like you so hungry to be on
that field, man. How did that affect you
not being able to kind of finish what
you started?
I actually seen like light from it, you
know, uh when you've been playing this
I've been playing this game for so long.
I've been playing since I was four years
old. And you know, when you you know, I
don't even think about getting hurt.
That's not even a thing of my mind. Like
I don't go out here and put in that that
I don't go out here and put dang if I if
I do this, I might get hurt. Like I I
think about hurting people. Like and I
know I'm not trying to sound like messed
up, but you know, as a mindset of a
football player, you know, you set your
mind. It's like it's like like Navy
Seals. they they get their they get
their their their task, they set and
they search and they destroy. You know,
that's the same thing with me. I get my
task and I I try to execute my my task
at a high level. And you know, uh I just
I just I was I'm more grateful for the
injury than anything because I was able
to look at life differently. you know,
uh, the first time being able to being
being not being able to play, you know,
I got a chance to, uh, embrace, you
know, life, you know, being able to have
all my ligaments and limbs and hands and
feet, you know, how how much of a
blessing that really is. And being able
to to to experience, you know, not being
able to walk for 3 months, you know, it
kind of you look at life completely
different, man. And and you look at life
and and you don't take life for granted.
And you know, uh, I feel like, you know,
I definitely had my my my ups and downs
with the recovery, but man, I'm here.
And that's all that's one thing like me
and my dad, my agent, just taking it one
day at a time, you know, just being able
to making sure we're doing everything
right, making sure I don't have any
setbacks and just being able to prepare
myself for this next season.
>> Well, you said you want to hurt people.
I'm telling you, there's not a fan in
the world of the Commanders that don't
want to hear that. They loving every
part of that, man. And when you end the
season with an injury and then you're
going into free agency, it's a lot of
questions in your mind, I'm sure, like,
what is my value going to be? How are
people going to be looking at me? But
even with that injury, there was still
value. People wanted you. The commander
said, "Yo, we got to bring him into the
building." That had to do something for
your confidence, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, I feel like, you know, uh,
people are not defined by injury. And
you know, uh, when you're when you're
down or you going through something like
this, you know, you kind of like try to
find stuff that's going to like kind of
bring you back to like to like
levelheaded and kind of bring you back
to like what you doing it for. And, you
know, if you if you look at a lot of
greats, and I'm not calling myself a
great, you know, but I'm still I'm
chasing that greatness. But you know,
uh, a lot of them great like Kobe and
you know, like shoot you could talk
about a uh Pat Mahomes, Tom Brady,
Michael Jordan, LeBron, Kobe, they all
had a speed bump in their in their
journey, you know, where they had
adversity
>> or they had to go through something or
they had to overcome something. And you
know, I feel like seeing those messages
and seeing how they overcame those is
like how you going to overcome this, you
know, like you know, you got to put
yourself in a situation like, okay, this
may have happened for a reason. How you
going to bounce back from it? So, I'm
I'm more looking to overcome and to
accomplish than more to
than like I I this ain't this ain't no
setback.
>> This ain't no setback. This is a uh this
is something I'mma overcome. This is
something I'm going to achieve.
>> And Tim, you've already overcome, right?
You in the building now. here now. Now
it's time to get to work. My last
question for you, Tim Settlement, what
are your goals for yourself heading into
this year? How can you help the Bernie
and Gold defense be just a little more
disruptive?
>> Just causing havoc every week. You know,
I I'm not the type of person to uh to
predict stats. You know, I go out here
and I play I line up one one down at a
time and I I try to oppose my will and I
try to help anybody around me. you know,
uh, my my goal is for us to be number
one defense, if not number one top
three, and for us to to be a contender
and to go to the Super Bowl. You know,
the the goals is not that it's not that
much goals. It's just uh
a mind to set task and to conquer.
>> Tim, I think we all there with you, my
brother. Again, congratulations.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Welcome home, my brother. Man, can't
wait to see you back in that burgundy
and gold, man.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes, sir. Commanders family. This is
Free Agency Fridays. Our next man up,
Tim Settle, back in the building to run
it back with the burgundy and go. We
appreciate your time, brother. Yes, sir.